http://www.lit.ie/en-ie/privacy

Research
Research within LIT occurs through 14 dedicated centres and groups encompassing a wide variety of...
Development
Development
The Development Unit is dedicated to implementing LITs vision of supporting individuals, companie...
Innovation
Innovation
LIT provides support to innovation and enterprise in the region using a wide variety of tools. To...
Mobile Search
Language:
Home
Current:
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
Cookie Statement
This statement relates to the privacy practices of Limerick Institute of Technology ("LIT") in connection with LIT's websites.
General statement
Limerick Institute of Technology fully respects your right to privacy and actively seeks to preserve the privacy rights of those who share personal information with LIT. For further information, please see the Data Protection section of this website.
Collection and use of personal information
LIT does not collect any personal information about you on its websites apart from information which you volunteer. Any personal information which you volunteer to LIT in connection with its websites will be treated in accordance with the Irish Data Protection Acts and the EU General Data Protection Regulation. Accordingly, LIT shall only process such information in line with our privacy notices.
Collection and use of technical information/cookies
This website uses cookies which are small text files placed on your computer so that LIT's website scripts can analyse how users use the website and record your preferences. The different types of cookies used on this website are as follows:
Essential Cookies
These cookies are essential for enabling user movement around our website. They do not gather information about you that could be used for marketing purposes and do not remember where you have been on the internet. If you wish to use our website, you cannot disable this category of cookies.
Analytics Cookies
We use Google Analytics to collect information about how visitors use our website. These cookies collect information in aggregate to provide us with an insight into how our website is being used. You may be able to delete these cookies through your browser settings. The following table provides more information about these cookies:
Source of Cookie
Name
Purpose
Google Analytics
_ga, _gat, _gid
These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. We do not record IP addresses.
Marketing Cookies
We use third party companies to assist us in targetting advertisements relating to LIT courses and services.
Source of Cookie
Name
Purpose
Facebook/Instagram
_fbp, fr, tr
These cookies are used by Facebook/Instagram and facilitate the delivery of retargeted advertisements on LIT courses to visitors of our site via Facebook.
Google Ad Words
ads/ga-audiences
These cookies are used by Google AdWords to re-engage visitors with targeted advertisements on LIT courses based on their behaviour during their site visit.
Third Party Cookies
Our website includes functionality provided by third parties. A common example is an embedded YouTube video. When you visit a page with content embedded from third parties such as Google, Twitter, YouTube or Facebook, these service providers may set their own cookies on your web browsers. For example, Facebook sets cookies via our website if you engage with any of the pages on our websites.
Further information on each of these third party provider’s cookie policy is available on their website.
Examples of third party cookies used on this website are set out below.
Source of Cookie
Name
Purpose
YouTube
GPS, IDE, PREF, test_cookie, visitors_info1_live, ysc, yt-remote-cast-installed, yt-remote-connected-devices, yt-remote-device-id, yt-remote-fast-check-period, yt-remote-session-app, yt-remote-session-name
Enables users to view embedded YouTube videos on all devices.
How to disable these cookies
LIT shall assume that you consent to the placement of these cookies on your device unless you specifically disable them. Users may disable these cookies from their web browser with no loss of functionality. This can be achieved through your browser settings - the help function within your browser should tell you how;
or you can learn how by visiting the websites referred to above.
Links
LIT is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of other websites. The privacy practices on these websites may differ from that on LIT's websites, and we advise that you review the other websites’ policies before providing personal information. Within the LIT domain (.lit.ie) you may find websites over which LIT has no editorial responsibility. Such sites can include the websites of student organisations, etc. While LIT expects compliance with this privacy statement at such sites, please contact helpdesk@lit.ie if you encounter LIT websites that are not compliant with this privacy and cookie statement.
Revisions to Cookie Statement
LIT may revise this cookie statement from time to time. Changes to this privacy statement will be posted here so you should periodically check this page to review the most recent statement. If you have any questions about this cookie statement or the practices of LIT's websites they should be referred to the Information and Compliance Officer at the address set out above.
Contact
Any queries or concerns about the use of cookies on this website should be sent by email to data.protection@lit.ie or addressed to the Information and Compliance Officer, Limerick Institute of Technology, Moylish Park, Limerick V94 EC5T, Ireland.
News & Events
News
Events
08 October 2020
AIT - LIT Consortium Awarded €5 Million to Progress TU Ambition
Continue reading
06 October 2020
LIT President & Chair of THEA Professor Vincent Cunnane has issued the following statement on behalf of the Presidents of the Institutes of Technology
Continue reading
05 October 2020
LIT’s Popular Careers Fair Goes Big and Goes Virtual as Companies Sign Up to Meet with LIT Talent Pool
Continue reading
21 September 2020
LIT’s Level 8 Construction Management Course Receives CABE Accreditation
Continue reading
18 September 2020
Irish Female Artists pave the way for their European counterparts, with the support of LSAD & the Wom@rt Programme
Continue reading
03 September 2020
LIT and The Design Craft Council of Ireland Launch Open Call for Craft Business Programme
